Ogooluwa Olutimilehin

WEB DEVELOPER

An enthusiastic web developer with hands-on experience in creating interactive and responsive web applications, translating designs, interacting with Rest APIs, code versioning and using external libraries to create rich interfaces. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate as part of a productive team.

+234 912 101 7814
extremeworkbench@gmail.com
Lagos, Nigeria





GitHub

Experience

Junior Web Developer

Glam's Haven | 2020 - 2021

- · Optimized home and landing pages
- Co-designed managed and monitored the company site for continuous development.
- Represented tech team at meetings with the executive and other team members.
- Weekly progress report and discussion of project goals and milestones.
- Optimization of the site for speed, performance, and high ranking on the web.

Junior Software Engineer

Securesoft Limited | 2022 - now

- Engaged in new business development, from a technical reference point in order to boost functionality and use-cases of software.
- Weekly progress report and discussion of project goals and milestones.
- Took part in social media management to boast engagement.

Education

Bachelors in Information Technology

Eastern Mediterranean University | 2017 - 2022 Graduated with High Honors

PERSONAL PROJECTS

(visit https://ogooluwanick-portfolio.netlify.app/)

Inventools - Graduation Project

iiii March 2021 - January 2022

- · Created a database with MongoDB
- Created user login and registration
- Inventory functionality and Categorization for with using React Hooks
- Page Routing using React Router
- Utilized node/express for the backend
- Used Semantic UI for the dashboard/and data tables.
- Used CSS/SASS for styling and User Interface design.

Echos - Blog Webapp

🚃 January 2022 - February 2022

- · Created a database with MongoDB
- · Made use of Google api for automatic login
- · Created custom user login and registration.
- Made use of Redux for state management.
- Page Routing using React Route.
- Utilized node/express for the backend.
- Used Material UI for the most major styling.
- Used SASS to make the site responsive

Calculator - HTML/CSS & Js

iii May 2021 - May 2021

- Collected input via DOM manipulation
- Utilized Js function to display proper output of the operation ·
- Using CSS I made a stunning User Interface

CURRENT INTERESTS

- React-native
- Micro Frontend Architecture
- Web3
- Data Analysis with Python

Skills

- HTML
- CSS/SCSS/SASS
- JavaScript
- ReactJs
- React-Native
- Redux (Redux Toolkit)
- · Git & Github
- Bootstrap/ Material UI
- Styled-Components
- Data Visualisation (recharts, chart.js)
- Front-End Development

Licenses & Certifications

- Responsive Web Design
 - Issued May 2022 · No Expiration Date
 - Credential ID fcc971fa9f7-36ac-48d3-931e-537e2125f000
- Front End Development Libraries
 - Issued July 2022 · No Expiration Date
 - Credential ID fcc971fa9f7-36ac-48d3-931e-537e2125f000
- <u>Fundamentals of digital marketing</u>
 - $\circ~$ Issued Apr 2022 \cdot No Expiration Date
 - o Credential ID PJN S8K V4K

DEPLOYMENT - CI/CD

- Netlify
- AWS